Yashovardhan Agrawal

| ■ yashovardhanagrawal@gmail.com | 🌴 yashovardhan.me

| 🖪 yashovardhanagrawal

Being involved in various open source communities, I have worked for many different sets of roles as an application developer or mentor, basically in JavaScript Development. Personally, I love making applications using React Native Redux and have about a year of experience working with the frameworks.

Education

The LNM Institute of Information Technology

Jaipur, India

B. TECH IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

August 2016 - Present

Work Experience

REDHAT JBoss Community

Remote

November 2017 - January 2018,

September 2018 - Present

- GOOGLE CODE-IN MENTOR 2017 & 2018
- Review their set tasks within a specified time limit.
- · As a token of appreciation, I got a chance to attend the Google Code-in meet-up in the Google Asia-Pacific Headquarters, Singapore

coala Remote

GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE MENTOR & CORE DEVELOPER

February 2018 - September 2018

- One of the main developers of the open source organization.
- I had mentored the GSoC Project named 'Meta Review/ Git Task List' by Yana Agun Siswanto under open source organization coala
- As a token for appreciation for my work, coala recommended my name for attending the GSoC Mentors' Summit in California
- Tech Stack: EmberJS, GitHub GraphQL API, GitLab API, Phabricator API, Wikidata Query API, Python, errbot, coala

· Mentor high school students trying to learn and contribute to open source projects with the JBoss Community

Biller Jaipur, Rajasthan

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

FOUNDER & MAINTAINER

April 2018 - Present

September 2017 - Present

- Main developer of the mobile User App and Waiter App for the Biller platform
- Managed the whole client side mobile application
- Made difference company specific components and sub modules incorporated into the applications
- The initial applications were built on Expo, which later on shifted to pure React Native.
- Tech Stack: React Native, Redux, Expo, Android & iOS Development, NodeJS, Thunk, RestAPI, ESLint, TravisCI

Addy Jaipur, India

Maintain the open source organization Addy (https://github.com/addy-org)

- Maintain the wiki pages of Addy (http://addy.wiki)
- This app became the inspiration for Google Plus Codes that works on a similar principle

Volunteer Work ___

GitHub Remote **CAMPUS EXPERT** October 2017 - Present

- India's 2nd GitHub Campus Expert
- · Manage the LNMIIT technical community and organizations with support from GitHub

YASHOVARDHAN AGRAWAL

Atal Innovation Mission, Govt. of India

Uttar Pradesh, India

MENTOR OF CHANGE

August 2018 – Present

- Mentor of Change Program is a strategic nation-building initiative to engage leaders who can guide and mentor students in thousands of Atal Tinkering Labs that Atal Innovation Mission has established/is in the process of establishing across India.
- I have been allotted a school in the rural areas of Ambedkar Nagar, Uttar Pradesh, India where I conduct mentoring sessions for the development of technical and entrepreneurial aspects within the underprivileged students

Hackference India 2018

Bengaluru, India

Co-Founder & CTO

- Hackference India is going to the biggest open source event across India. We are organizing a deliquescent combination of Hackathon, DevRelCon and Hiring Fair, that serves to every kind of aspirations.
- I am one of the main ideators and the head community manager at Hackference India 2018
- · Along with that, my work includes the handling of the technology aspects of the event

Cybros - The Computer Club LNMIIT

Jaipur, India

July 2018 – Present

SUB COORDINATOR - FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT

August 2018 - Present

- · Cybros is the main computer activity club in LNMIIT, which aims promote the coding culture within the college community
- As a Sub Coordinator in Frontend division, my aim is to organize different workshops and events within the community, aiding to the student pursuing or willing to pursue the field.

Computer Society of India - LNMIIT Jaipur Chapter

Jaipur, India

OPEN SOURCE LEAD

April 2018 - Present

- Computer Society of India is a college chapter of the main CSI Foundation across India. Within this community, we aim to conduct classes and tutorials of different fields of computer science.
- As the open source lead, I manage the GitHub organization and the Semester Long Projects repositories that are undertaken by the students. Along with that, my aim is conduct workshops and regular classes on open source development, git & GitHub facilitating the interests of students toward open source.

Projects

Blood Connect Mobile App (under development

REACT NATIVE, REDUX, EXPO, ESLINT, TRAVISCI

To better manage the whole processes in Blood Connect (which are currently maintained using Google Sheets, we came up with an idea to develop an application that will be connected to our database and help us manage the donors, and requesters more efficiently. This project is currently under development.

 $\verb|https://expo.io/@yashovardhanagrawal/blood-connect|$

https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/blood-connect

GitHub Campus Experts Mobile App

REACT NATIVE, EXPO, ESLINT, TRAVISCI

Voluntarily developed a simple React Native based application for GitHub Campus Experts. This can seen as a nice implementation of react-navigation & react-native-elements libraries, along with MapView & Geocoding.

https://expo.io/@yashovardhanagrawal/GitHub-Campus-Experts

https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/gce-mobile

React Native Lifecycle Methods

REACT NATIVE, EXPO, ESLINT, TRAVISCI

A simple app made to demonstrate the use of lifecycle methods in React Native

https://expo.io/@yashovardhanagrawal/blood-connect

 $\verb|https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/react-native-lifecycle-methods|$

Honors & Awards ____

2018	GitHub Universe & Experts Summit Invitee, GitHub	San Francisco, Calfornia
2018	GSoC Mentor's Summit Invitee, Google	Sunnyvale, California
2018	OpenTechNight Winner, FOSSASIA Summit	Singapore
2017	Finalist, Sabre Hackathon	BITS Goa
2017	Finalist, Hack in the North - 2.0	IIIT Allahabad
2016	Winner, LNMHacks	LNMIIT Jaipur